<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
<body>
<section name="Jelly tags provided by the Java.net plugin">
  <p>
    The Java.net plugin provides the following Jelly tags that may be used in Jelly script in
    <code>maven.xml</code> and other plugins. In order to make use of these tags you must 
    first import them with an appropriate <code>xmlns</code> directive, referencing the URI
    '<code>javanet</code>' (without quotes).
  </p>
	<table border="1">
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<td>Tag</td>
				<td>Description</td>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <code><strong>deploy</strong></code>
        </td>
        <td>
          <source>&lt;javanet:deploy [failonerror="<strong>true</strong>|false"]&gt; ... &lt;/javanet:deploy&gt;</source>
          <p>
            Deploys a set of artifacts to the project's CVS for inclusion in the
            site-wide Maven repository.
          </p>
          
          <p>
            The actual artifacts to deploy are specified via nested <code>artifact</code>
            elements. Setting the <em>failonerror</em> attribute to false allows the build
            to continue if the deployment fails for any reason.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <code><strong>artifact</strong></code>
        </td>
        <td>
        <source>&lt;javanet:artifact path="path/to/artifact" 
                     [type="jar|war|plugin|dist"]  
                     [withpom="<strong>true</strong>|false"] /&gt;</source>

          <p>
            Defines a single artifact within a <code>deploy</code> tag. Each artifact that is
            to be deployed must be referenced by an <code>artifact</code> tag containing at least
            the artifact path.
          </p>
          
          <p>
            The specified path should relatively or absolutely reference the local artifact file
            that is to be deployed. With artifacts of type <code>jar</code>, <code>war</code>, or
            <code>distribution</code> the <em>type</em> attribute is optional, since the tag will
            determine the type from the file extension. <code>plugin</code> artifacts will need to
            be explicitly stated however, since they are packaged as <code>.jar</code> files.
          </p>

          <p>
            The optional <em>withpom</em> attribute allows you to disable copying of the
            POM. This is useful in situations where you know the POM for this version already
            exists in the repository, for example when deploying multiple artifacts of a single
            type (as done with <code>distribution</code> artifacts) or deploying several artifact
            types from the same project.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
</section>
</body>
</document>
